akari ga oreba kage ga dekiru to itta
You said if there's light, there are shadow
ano hi no kimi no koe ga wasure rarezu ni
I can't forget the words you said that day
tsuyoku aritai to negai
I wish to be strong
rousoku wo keshita yubi
I put out the candle with my finger
hi no watsusa ni inochi wo oboete
The heat of the flames reminded me of life
boku no koa ga hajikeru
The core of my being bursts open
guren no ai ga kokoro wo yaite
This red-hot love burns my heart
kaze ni mayoe ba namida ga ochiru
While wandering in the wind, tears start to fall
kizutsuki nagara mirai shinjite
Though I'm hurt, I believe in the future
mata saki e sono saki e
Let's go further and further ahead
gareki no sora wa bokura no kizuna
The rubble in the sky is our bond
osou mayakashi kechirashite yaru
I'll cut through the attempts to deceive me
tatakai no hate ni nani mo nakutemo
Even if there's nothing at the end of the battle
mata saki e sono saki e Ikou
Let's go further and further ahead
Kakashi: Shadow of the Anbu
Jonin Leader
（ガイ）おう！　カカシではないか！
Hey, Kakashi!
こっちで一緒に
だんごを食わんか？
Come join us for
some sweet dumplings!
うん？
《カカシ：俺が下忍の担当上忍？》
Me? A jonin leader
in charge of genin?
《ミナト先生…》
Minato Sensei...
((カカシ：遅いぞ　オビト！
You're late, Obito!
（ミナト）やっと来たね！　キミがオビトか。
You're finally here...
You must be Obito.
（リン）待ってたよ。
We've been waiting for you.
（オビト）ハァ…　ギリか…。
大遅刻だよ！
Barely made it...
You're really late.
もう自己紹介は終わっている。
あとはキミだけ。
We've already introduced ourselves.
You're the only one left!
俺は　火影になる！
I'm going to be the Hokage!
うちはオビトだ！
My name's Obito Uchiha!
んでもって　俺の火影岩には
トレードマークのゴーグルと→
For my Great Stone Face,
make sure my trademark goggles and
Sharingan are nicely carved out!
更に　写輪眼も
しっかり彫ってもらう！
それで
他里に　ニラミをきかせてやんのだ！
So I can glare over
the neighboring lands!
はぁ…。
写輪眼でメンチきってる→
I'll scare the hell out of them
with my Sharingan stare...
俺の火影岩にビビッて→
ここには手を出さねえようにな！
and no one will
dare attack our village!
そんなのは　火影になって
写輪眼を開眼してから注文しろ！
Rattle off your instructions
after you become the Hokage
and activate your Sharingan.
だいたい　ゴーグルしてたら
写輪眼は彫れないだろ！
Besides, how can they carve the Sharingan
if you're wearing goggles?
ゴーグルの上から
彫ればいいだろうが！
They can carve it out over my goggles!
それだと
目が飛び出てるみたいになるね。
Then it will look like your eyeballs
are popping out.
とにかく　俺と同じ夢を持ってる
部下ができて嬉しいよ。
Anyway... I'm happy that someone on
this team shares my dream.
今日から　キミの上司になるミナトだ。
よろしく！
I'm Minato.
From today, I'll be your superior.
I'm glad to meet you!
おう！
Yeah!
ハハッ！　ともかく
４人で最初の演習をやるよ。
All right, let's have
our first practice together.
は　はい！
Y-Yes!
この演習は　キミたちの
チームワークを見るためだ。
In this training session,
I want to see your teamwork.
チームワーク？
Teamwork?
この２つの鈴を
僕からとれたら演習終了。
Take these two bells away from me,
and practice will be over.
簡単だろ。
Simple, right?
鈴が２つということは…。
え？
Two bells mean...
そういうこと！
Exactly.
え？　どういうこと？
Huh? What does it mean?
３人のうち
１人は脱落ってことだ。
One of us will be dropped
from the team.
えっ！？
What?!
(察しがいいね！
さあ　はじめるよ))
Good observation.
Okay... Let's start.
俺がお前たちの
担当上忍となった→
I'm your jonin leader, Hatake...
はたけ…。
カカシ先生だろ！
Kakashi Sensei, right?
あいさつなんて
どうだっていいから→
Never mind the formalities...
さっさと始めようぜ！
Let's just get started!
お前たちにやってもらうのは
脱落率６６％…。
What you're going to do...
has a failure rate of 66%.
《あの演習のとき　俺は
チームワークなんて考えちゃいなかった。
During that practice,
I wasn't even thinking of teamwork.
そして　そのことを
ミナト先生は気づかなかった》
And Minato Sensei
didn't even notice it.
((みんな合格だ！
You all pass!
このままチームワークを高めていこうね。
Let's strengthen
our teamwork even more!
(オッス！
はい！))
– Right!
– Yes!
つまり　お前らのうち１人は→
In other words, one of you will definitely
be sent back to the Academy.
確実にアカデミーへと
戻されるってわけだ。
《ミナト先生が
気づかなかったのも無理はない。
It's no wonder Minato Sensei
didn't notice.
俺は　チームワークと見せかけ
２人を利用した》
I pretended to work with the team
and used the other two.
《手加減してくれているのは
わかる。
I know he's giving us a break...
だが　ミナト先生のレベルは高すぎる。
But Minato Sensei is way too skilled.
俺一人じゃどうにもならない》
There's no way I can do it alone.
((惜しい！
Close!
まだまだその程度じゃ
とられるわけにはいかないよ。
Whoa...
You'll never get it
at the rate you're going.
《やはりそうだ！
I knew it.
ミナト先生は相手に合わせて
手加減のレベルを変えている！
Minato Sensei is making
an allowance for our skill levels!
オビトやリンに対するときと…。
Compared to how he is
against Obito and Rin...
俺に対する時とでは→
With me,
he doesn't ease up as much.
あきらかに手の抜き方が違う。
このままなら　１００％
鈴を奪うことはできない。
At this rate,
I'm definitely not getting a bell.
任務を達成するためには…》
In order to complete this mission...
オビト　リン。
Obito! Rin!
アカデミーでやった
最初のフォーメーションだ。
The first formation we learned
at the academy!
はぁ？
あんな単純なフォーメーションが→
Huh?
I doubt if a simple formation like that
would work against Minato Sensei.
ミナト先生に通用するとは
思えないけど…。
やるんだ！
Just do it!
やってみなけりゃ　わからないか。
I guess it's worth a try.
何もしねえよりはマシだな。
It's better than doing nothing...
その作戦　のってやるよ。
Okay, I'm in!
(いくぞ！
おう！
ええ))
Here we go!
– Yeah!
– Right!
《カカシ：ミナト先生が見せる
唯一の隙。
I see only one opening
with Minato Sensei.
そこを狙うために　２人を
おとりに使えば　チャンスはある》
If I use these two to trap him,
we have a chance!
さあ　始めようか。
Okay, let's start
《あんなのは
チームワークなんかじゃない。
That wasn't teamwork.
あのとき　ミナト先生が　俺に
チームワークの素養が欠けていると→
Back then, if only
Minato Sensei had seen
that something was missing
in our teamwork...
判断してくれていれば…》
ああ！
お先に鈴をとらせてもらうぜ。
Thanks for letting me get the bell first!
脱落は　お前で決まりだな。
Looks like you're going
to be left behind!
《そうじゃない　あれは…。
No...
That wasn't... Minato Sensei's fault!
あれは
ミナト先生のせいなんかじゃない》
《俺は責任を転嫁して→
I'm just trying to pass the buck,
and running away from the truth...
現実から
逃げようとしているだけだ。
だからこそ…。
That's why...
コイツらのチームワークを
見極めねばならん》
with these guys...
I'm going to make sure
their teamwork is solid.
無様だな。
You're so clumsy...
名門の名がすたるぜ。
You're a disgrace.
はぁ！？　そりゃ　お前のことだろ。
Huh?! Speak for yourself!
いやだね　やだやだ。
Damn it... Of all the luck...
こんな連中と
同レベルで扱われるなんてな。
To be lumped together
with guys like you.
なに！？
ハハハハハ！
Say that again!
沸く　沸く！
お茶が　ヘソで沸くってなもんだぜ。
This is hilarious.
You guys are so ridiculous!
なあ　俺　いいこと
思いついちゃったぜ。
Say, I just had a great idea.
奇遇だな
俺も思いついたことがあるんだ。
What a coincidence. Me too.
ヘッ。
ヘヘッ　俺もだ。
Me too!
先生に手間かけさせるのも
悪いからな。
We don't want to give Sensei
a hard time...
だな。　脱落者は…。
I agree! So I...
お。
れ。
が。
– will...
– decide...
（３人）決めてやるよ！
- ...who drops out!
お前ら…。
You guys.
はぁ～！！
だ…。
えっ？
Huh?
お前ら全員　落第だ。
You all fail!
アカデミーから　やり直してこい。
You're going back to the academy.
《あの凍りついた視線…》
That frozen gaze...
《まるで　あやつの心の闇
そのものじゃな。
It's darkness itself...
His darkness hasn't been dispelled yet.
あやつの闇を晴らすには
まだ時が必要か》
More time is necessary...
リン　オビト…。
Rin... Obito...
わかってる。
チームワークを大切にしないヤツを→
I know.
I have no intention of making people
who don't work as a team into shinobi...
忍にするつもりなんてないよ。
誰が　なんと言おうとな。
No matter what anyone says...
さて　今年は　どうなることやら。
Now then...
How will this year turn out...?
たぁっ！　それ！
たぁっ！
そんなことでは
アカデミーへ逆戻りだぞ！
Keep it up and you'll end up back
at the academy!
（リー）うぉ～っ　青春フルパワーです！
I'm in the spring of youth
at full power!
（ネジ）くっ…　さすが上忍。
No wonder he's a jonin.
俺の体術が軽く　いなされていく。
He dodges my taijutsu
with such ease.
（テンテン）もう　アカデミー卒業したら
下忍だと思ってたのに。
I thought graduating from
the academy made us genin.
落第なんて
しゃれにならないわよ！
Failing now is too embarrassing!
木ノ葉　剛力旋風！
Severe... Leaf Hurricane!
（３人）うわ～っ！
もう降参か？
Giving up already?
諦めません！
I'm not giving up!
僕の夢は
体術のみで立派な忍となること。
My dream is to become a great shinobi
through taijutsu alone!
その夢を
諦めるわけにはいかないのです！
I cannot... abandon my dream!
フンッ　つまらん。
That's ridiculous...
だが　俺とて　ここで
立ち止まるわけにはいかない！
But...
I'm not throwing in the towel either!
そうよ。　憧れの
くのいちに近づくんだから。
That's right!
I'm that close to becoming
the kunoichi I've always admired!
へこたれてなんかいられない！
No way am I calling it quits!
（ガイ）う～ん　いいぞ　みんな！
Now you're talking, guys!
青春しているじゃないか！
That's how youth should be!
さぁ　体力が限界をこえようとも→
Even if you've used up
every ounce of your energy...
気力を振り絞れ！
suck it up and push through it!
よ～し　この俺に
渾身の一撃を入れてみろ！
Hit me with all your might!
うぉ～っ！
ああ～っ！
（３人）いくぞ！
– Here we come!
お前ら！
The three of you...
全員　合格だ！
... all pass!
やりました！
Yes! I did it!
僕は　やりましたよ！
I did it!
く　苦しい…。
I-I can't breathe...!
ぷは～っ！
全員　合格できて　よかったですね。
I'm so happy we all made it!
こんなところで
つまずくわけにはいかないからな。
I wasn't about to fail
after coming this far.
でも　あの噂の先生じゃなくて
よかったね。
But...
Thank goodness we didn't get
the sensei everyone talks about.
前回　３人ともアカデミーへ
送り返したという→
You mean that jonin who sent the three
before us back to the academy?
あの上忍のことですか？
うん。
実力に運も不運もない。
Uh-huh.
Luck has nothing to do
with real strength.
ソイツらに力がなかっただけのこと。
Those guys just weren't
good enough.
そうでもないらしいわよ。
That's not what I heard.
なんでも　忍としての力よりも
大切なものがあるとかなんとか。
It was about what's even more important
than a shinobi's strength or something...
それは何でしょう？
And what is that?
やはり　一撃必殺の
すごい必殺技でしょうか？
Is it some kind of
super-lethal-one-hit technique?
（ネジ）何にしても
自分勝手な基準を→
But who does he think he is
to make up his own criteria?
押しつけられては　たまらんな。
《カカシよ…》
Kakashi...
兄ちゃん　本当にいいのかい？
Are you sure about this,
big brother?
俺たちだけで
弁当を食うなんて。
Maybe we shouldn't eat
the bento lunches...
俺の言ったことが
間違ってたなんて→
Look, have I ever been wrong?
今まであったか？　ないだろ！
でも　カカシ先生は　いないよ。
But Kakashi Sensei's not here.
つべこべ言うな！
Quit nitpicking!
お前たちは言われたとおり
ルールを守ればいいんだ。
You two, just listen and follow the rules!
((オビト：確かに忍の世界で→
Sure, in the world of Ninja,
(ルールや掟を破るヤツは
クズ呼ばわりされる))
one who breaks the rules and regulations
is regarded as scum...
((けどな　仲間を大切にしないヤツは
それ以上のクズだ！))
But those who abandon their comrades...
are worse than scum!
《オビト…　俺は…》
Obito... I...
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei...!
俺は落第かもしれないけど
弟たちは　ルールを守ったんだ！
I've failed, but my kid brothers
followed the rules!
お前たちは…。
The three of you...
お前たちは俺の命令を守った。
Each of you obeyed my orders.
ルールを守った。
だが　忍にとって→
You stuck to the rules.
But you didn't follow what
is most important to a shinobi...
もっとも大切なものを
守れなかった。
何だ　そりゃ？
白髪野郎！
What is that?!
You grey-haired...!
お前らも　アカデミーで学び直してこい。
You're all going back to
the academy to figure it out.
（アスマ）中忍試験を見送った？
Passed on the Chunin Exams?
ガイ　お前にしては慎重だな。
That's unusually cautious of you, Guy.
ああ。
Yeah...
((リー：えっ　中忍試験ですか！？
Huh? The Chunin Exams?
そうだ　形式上８回以上
任務をこなしていれば→
Yes.
The way the system works is,
if you complete over eight missions...
中忍試験に参加する資格がある。
you qualify to participate
in the Chunin Exams.
ここしばらくは　ルーキーが中忍試験に
参加したことはないんだが→
There haven't been rookies
in the Chunin Exams lately...
どうだ　出てみるか？
Would you like to go for it?
はっ…。
Uh...!
あん？　どうした　リー？
Huh? What's wrong, Lee?
はい　自分の実力が
どの程度なのか→
Well... I'd like to test myself
to see how strong I am...
試してみたい…
その思いはあります。
I do have that desire...
でも…。
（ガイ）でも　なんだ？
But...
But what?
僕の実力が
試すに値しないことは→
I don't deserve to take the test
at my present level.
僕自身が
いちばんわかっています！
I know my own ability best!
（ガイ）ふむ　ネジはどうする？
What about you, Neji?
フッ…　俺も今回は　パスだ。
I'll pass on it too.
え～っ！？　ネジなら
すぐにでも中忍になれるのに！
Huh?
Neji, you'd make it to chunin
in no time!
だからこそ　急ぐ意味はない。
That's why there's no point
in rushing.
そうか　では　テンテンは？
I see. And you, Tenten?
なら　私も！　次の試験までに→
Then I'll pass too!
Let's train hard and take
the next exams together!
修業をつんで
３人一緒に受けましょう！
(みんな！
お前ら！))
You guys!
You guys...
俺は　お前たちのような
弟子を持って嬉しいぞ！
Having students like you
makes me very happy!
だんごだ！
だんごのおかわりをくれ！
Dumplings! Another order
of dumplings, please!
は～い！
Coming right up!
よくわからんが　お前らしいな。
I don't get it...
But this is so like you.
（紅）それよりも
アカデミーを卒業したばかりの→
By the way, what's it like to be
in charge of fresh academy graduates?
下忍を受け持つって　どんな気分？
そうか　お前は
今回が初めてだったな。
That's right. This is your first time.
ん？　おい　カカシ！
Hmm?
Hey, Kakashi!
どうだ　お前も一緒に
こっちで　だんごを食わないか？
Come join us for some
sweet dumplings!
なんだ　アイツ？
What's with him?
まるで暗部にいた頃のような
暗い目をしていた。
His eyes are as cold as ever...
like he never left the ANBU.
前回も全員
落としたらしいわね。
He failed every one of them again.
それは　たいした問題じゃない。
That's not such a big deal.
ああ　それよりも問題なのは
カカシの心に巣くう闇のほうだ。
No, but the darkness in
Kakashi's heart is a problem.
まだ引きずってるのね。
He's still carrying that around...
私だって同期だったのよ。
悲しんだわ。
They were my classmates too.
And I grieved as well, but...
でも　いつかは立ち直らなきゃ。
You've got to get over it...
だな。
I know...
うむ　暗部なんて
陰気なところにいるから→
I knew that the depressing atmosphere of
the ANBU would turn him more sullen.
鬱々としていくんだと
思っていたんだが…。
((三代目　カカシのヤツは
暗部には向いていません！
Lord Third!
The ANBU isn't for someone
like Kakashi!
火影様に意見など
おこがましいのは承知しています。
I know it isn't my place
to say this, Lord Third!
でも　私たちは友を
仲間を多く失いすぎました！
But...
We've lost too many of our friends...!
今のカカシを見ていると
まるで死に急いでいるようで。
Watching Kakashi...
It's as though he's in a hurry to die...
だから我々は　カカシに下忍を
任せてはどうかと考えたのです。
That's why... we came up with this idea
to put him in charge of the genin...
アイツも弟子を持てば考え方も
変わっていくと思うのです。
If he has subordinates to look after,
we're sure he'll change...
ふむ　お前たちも　そう思うか。
Hmm... You think so too?
(それでは…))
So then...?!
はぁ　俺たちは　よけいなことを
したのかもしれんな。
Maybe we shouldn't have interfered...
暗部にいて
忍の闇を見続けるより→
We each thought that rather
than being in the ANBU,
未来の忍たちを
指導することのほうが→
being in charge of young future shinobi
held more promise for him, but...
希望を見いだしやすいと
思ったのだが…。
三代目！
三代目？
Lord Third!
Lord Third?
うお～　三代目！？
Lord Third?!
まあよい。
そのまま茶を続けなさい。
At ease, finish your tea.
わしも一杯もらうとしよう。
In fact, I'll have a cup too.
なるほどのう。　ホホホホホ…。
I see...
何がおかしいんです？
あなたはいつも→
What's so funny?
You always treat us like we're kids...
我々を子供扱いして…。
アスマ！
Asuma!
いや　笑ってすまなんだ。
Oh... Forgive me for laughing.
だが　子供扱いしたのは
確かにそうじゃ。
I must admit that I do treat you
like children.
《カカシ：ミナト先生　俺のやり方は
間違っているんでしょうか？》
Minato Sensei...
Is my way wrong...?
（みんな）カカシ先生！
– Kakashi Sensei!
は　はい？
Y-Yes?
– Good morning, sir!
（みんな）チーッス！
カカシ先生　俺たち今
アカデミーのしつけ担当をしてるんす。
Kakashi Sensei!
We're in charge of
academy discipline now!
やっぱり基本は
挨拶からだなってね。
We realized everything starts
with a proper greeting!
今の挨拶は　そこそこよかったぞ。
That greeting was spot on!
次も　しっかりやるんだぞ。
Keep it up!
（みんな）は～い！
– Yes!
それじゃ　失礼します。
（２人）失礼します！
Please excuse us!
– Excuse us!
（みんな）失礼します！
((挨拶なんてどうだっていいから
さっさと始めようぜ))
Who cares about greetings?
Let's get started.
アイツらがねぇ…。
Those guys, huh...
カカシ先生じゃないですか。
It's Kakashi Sensei!
ん？
お前たちは…。
It's you!
（３人）ありがとうございました！
– Thank you very much!
え？　えっ！？
W-What?!
俺たち　あの演習で
カカシ先生に落第くらって。
Thank you for failing us in that practice...
変わることができたんです。
は？
we were able to change!
Huh?
今までずっと
兄ちゃんに頼りっぱなしで→
We always depended
on our big brother...
and never stood up for ourselves...
自分の意見なんて
言ったことなくって。
本当は　あのときだって→
Actually, that time, we wanted to
share our lunch with him!
兄ちゃんに
弁当を食べさせたかったんです。
だから　あの演習のあと
俺たちも自分の意見を→
After the practice, we realized
that we should've spoken up
ちゃんと言わなきゃって。　ね？
うん。
and told you how we felt. Right?
Yeah...
弟たちを引っ張るつもりが
いつの間にか→
I thought I was helping them,
but I was stifling them instead.
弟たちの意見を
つぶしてたなんて。
俺も反省しました。
I learned a lesson too.
（３人）だから
カカシ先生には感謝しています！
– And so...!
– We're so grateful to you, Kakashi Sensei!
《感謝？　俺に？》
Grateful... to me...?
師は弟子に修業を与え
そして弟子から学ぶのじゃよ。
A teacher trains his students...
and at the same time,
learns from them.
そうやって　互いに高め合い
成長していく間柄こそ→
Only through mutual respect
and growth...
can you foster
a true teacher-pupil relationship.
本当の師弟と呼べるのじゃ。
It is my hope that you will nurture
such a relationship with your pupils.
お前たちにも　立派な師弟関係を
築いてくれることを望んでいる。
もちろん　カカシにも　な。
Of course, I wish it for Kakashi as well.
三代目　それ　もしかして…。
Lord Third!
Is that...
おっと　まだ極秘だがな。
Oh... it's still very secret.
カカシが今年　担当することとなる
アカデミーの卒業生じゃ。
But this is the list of
academy graduates
who will be under Kakashi's tutelage.
なかなかの個性派ぞろいじゃろ。
I'm sure it's a group of
highly individualistic kids.
NINJA DATA
kidzuite ndaro sou sekai ga kataru itsuwari to
I'm sure you've realized by now that the world tells lies
amai wana ni soko ni wa hontou nante nai koto o
And lays alluring traps, but there's no truth behind them
riyuu sagashite run away why? sono mewotojiteru no?
Search for a reason Run away Why?
Why are you closing your eyes?
tell me why can't you
Tell me why can't you
shinjitsu ni te o nobase!
Reach out for the truth!
always (sakebe shout out) all time (tsukame catch up)
Always (Scream, Shout out)
All the time (Catch it, Catch up)
everybody knows (we are the seeker get fire!!!)
Everybody knows (We are the seeker Get fire!!!)
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
tsuyoku aritai to negau nonaraba
if you firmly wish for it
narase narase mezame no kane o
Ring, ring the bell of awakening
koyoi tsuki no shita de kokoro sakebe
Shout from your heart under the moon tonight
utae utae hoero hoero
Sing, sing, howl, howl,
kibou no hikari o nozomu nonaraba
if you want the light of hope
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
akai tsuki no shita de kimi o sakebe
Shout to you under the red moon
ima ima ima flame up (catch the fire)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Catch the fire)
ima ima ima flame up (blaze up!!!)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Blaze up!!!)
I'm sure this new batch of genin
will hold your interest.
[スピーカ]皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Where are we?
This is Naruto's house.
[スピーカ]美空ひばりです。
Lord Fourth's orphan...
[スピーカ]では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Are you our sensei?
I'm Naruto Uzumaki,
I'm going to be Hokage!
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Squad Seven"
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の
豪華な歌手の皆さんによる→
華麗なステージを　お届けいたします。
That kid is a genin?